有时在夜深人静的时候
Sometimes Dr. Lecter and I would talk
汉尼拔医生会和我聊聊天
when things got quiet enough
谈我所选修的科学课程
about the science courses I was takin'.
那种邮购的心理学课程 也能称为科学?
Some kind of mail-order courses in psychology, Nurse Barney?
当然不是
No, sir.
我并不认为心理学是科学
I don't consider psychology a science
汉尼拔医生也不这么想
and neither did Dr. Lecter.
那么 巴尼...
Now, Barney...
当你在收容所工作的时候
while you were working at the asylum
你的确看到史黛琳和汉尼拔之间有互动关系
you observed Clarice Starling and Hannibal Lecter interacting.
互动?
Interacting?
就是聊天之类的
Talking to one another.
是的 他们看起来好像是...
Yes. Yes, it seemed to me that they...
我知道你很想拿这笔咨询费
I can see you're eager to justify your consulting fee
但是只说你看到的
but why don't we start with what you saw
别把自己的想法加进去
not what you thought about what you saw?
柯德 别这样 他当然可以表达自己的意见
Cordell, don't be like that. Barney can give us his opinion.
巴尼 告诉我们你的看法
Barney, give us your opinion of what you saw.
你觉得他们之间是哪种关系?
What was it between them?
通常汉尼拔医生根本不理会来访的观察员
Most of the time, Dr. Lecter didn't respond at all to visitors.
甚至会不发一言的瞪着前来观察的学生
He'd just, for instance, open his eyes long enough
好让他们觉得难堪
to insult some academic who was there to look over him.
但是他却回答史黛琳的问话
With Starling, he answered her questions.
她引起了他的兴趣 也被她深深的吸引住
She interested him. She intrigued him.
他认为她既迷人又有趣
He thought she was charming and amusing.
所以史黛琳和汉尼拔...
So Clarice Starling and Hannibal Lecter...
就变成了朋友
became friendly.
不错 是一种形而上的朋友
Inside a kind of formal structure, yes.
这么说来他很喜欢她?
And he was fond of her.
是的
Yes.
巴尼 谢谢你
Thank you, Barney.
谢谢你的坦白
Thank you very much for your candor.
至于你卖给我的那些...
And keep all those wonderful items...
汉尼拔的珍贵收藏品
from your personal Lecter treasure trove coming.
我非常喜欢
I've enjoyed them immensely.
维杰先生
Mr. Verger.
喔 我差点忘了
Oh, I almost forgot.
柯德 我能吃块甜点吗?
I might be able to get a cookie down. What do you say, Cordell?
那会要了你的命
I think it would kill you.
-多少钱?  -二十五...万
-How much? -Two hundred and fifty...thousand.
去开张二十五万的支票
Cut a check for $250,000.
片名:  汉尼拔
■
这种时候她也能睡?
How can she sleep at a time like this?
她昨晚出勤 现在正养精蓄锐
She's on a jump-out squad all night. She's saving her strength.
听说从华府警局 来了个叫柏顿的家伙
We got some guy named Bolton from the DC Police.
大家请注意 这是现场区域图
All right, everyone. Pay attention. Here's the layout.
抱歉 我是华府警探柏顿
Excuse me. I'm Officer Bolton, DC Police.
你好 从警徽上我可以看出来
I can see that from your badge. How do you do?
我是这里的负责人
I'm in charge here.
柏顿警探 我是史黛琳探员
Officer Bolton, I'm Special Agent Starling.
为了避免不必要的误会
Just so we don't get off on the wrong foot
让我解释一下我们来此的目的
let me explain why we're all here.
我对艾微达很了解 因为我曾逮捕过她两次
I'm here because I know Evelda Drumgo. I arrested her twice on RICO warrants.
这次因为牵涉到毒品和枪械
DEA and ATF, in addition to backing me up
禁药取缔局和武器管理局 也一起参加行动
are here for the drugs and the weapons.
至于你来这里是因为 市长在被判了使用可卡因罪后
You're here because our mayor wants to appear tough on drugs
为了表现出取缔毒品的决心
especially after his own cocaine conviction
才让你们加入我们的行动
and hopes he can accomplish that by having you join us here today.
小姐 你倒挺凶的嘛
You got a smart mouth, lady.
如果你不介意 我们可以继续讨论吗?
If you wouldn't mind, I'd appreciate it if you'd let me continue.
好 大家看一下
All right, take a look.
鲜鱼市场的后面是水
Fish market. Back's on the water.
对面是毒品制造所
Across the street, ground floor, is the meth lab.
"通缉犯"艾微达是爱滋病患者
Evelda Drumgo's HIV positive.
紧要关头她会又抓又咬 你们要小心
She will spit and bite if cornered, so you should watch it.
万一是你在媒体前送她进警车
If you happen to be the one who puts her in a patrol car in front of the news cameras
柏顿 千万别碰她的头
Bolton,you don't wanna push her head down.
因为她喜欢把针藏在头发里
She'll likely have a needle in her hair.
最好能在室内将她拿下"公共市场"
We want to take her inside the building, not out in the street.
大家尽量靠近我们的伪装车
We can get closest with the van.
到时候我们从前面进攻 禁药组攻打后面
If it looks good, on my signal we hit the front, DEA hits the back
请华府警探去支援禁药组
DCPD backin'them up.
她的瞭望员会守在三条街前
She'll have her watchers out at least three blocks around.
以便及时给她消息 所以我们不要太招摇
They've tipped her before in time, so let's not make spectacles of ourselves.
-今天挺忙碌的  -没错
-Pretty busy today. -I agree.
请给我杯咖啡
Can I please get a cup of coffee?
-你看到了吗?  -那表示可以行动
-Did you see that? -That's a roger.
嘿 近来如何?
What's up, man?
该死 她出来了
Goddamn it. It's her.
有三个人 都带着枪
With three guys. They're all packin'.
她胸前挂着东西 是婴儿
She's carryin' something. She's got a baby.
柏汉 人太多
Hey, Brigham, it's too crowded.
我看取消比较好
There are too many people. I say we call it off.
你说呢?
What do you say?
我同意
I agree.
所有单位 行动取消
All units, stand down.
-威士基知道了  -柏克知道了
-Whiskey team copies. -Burke copy.
这是柏顿 我要继续行动
This is Bolton. Stay on target.
柏顿 我已说过取消行动
I said all units stand down, Bolton, right now.
-太晚了 我们已经开始  -柏顿 请你合作
-It's too late. We're movin'in. -Bolton, he said it's off.
不准行动
Stand down now.
因为她胸前有婴儿 重复她有婴儿
She's carrying a baby. I repeat, she's carrying a baby.
所有单位不要行动
All units stand down.
-柏顿 把枪收起来  -要命 有人拿枪
-Keep that gun down, Bolton. -Damn, dude got a piece.
-先杀了他  -快走!
-Light his ass up. -It's a go!
调查局 快趴在地上
FBI! Down on the ground!
停火!
Hold it!
不要开枪
Hold your fire!
别开枪!
Don't!
艾微达 你出来!
Evelda, get out of the car!
是史黛琳吗?
Starling, is that you?
请你离开车子!
Step away from the car!
把手举起来
Show me your hands, Evelda.
请把手举起来
Please. Show me your hands.
你近来好吗?
How've you been?
别这样做
Don't do this.
做什么?
Do what?
好了 不会有事的
It's all right. It's okay.
我知道 宝贝 你吓坏了
I know, I know. Baby, I know.
别哭
It's okay.
你别哭
没事的
It's okay.
今早朋友 家人和同事 聚集在阿灵顿国家公墓中
Friends, family and coworkers gathered here this morning at Arlington National Cemetery
参加因公殉职的武器管制局柏汉探员的丧礼
to bury BATF Agent John Brigham shot and killed in the line of duty Friday.
他享年四十岁
He was 40 years old.
这场毒品突击 夺去他及另外五个人的生命
This ill-fated drug raid that claimed his life and five others
这一连串的意外事件 始于德州的瓦库
is the latest in a seemingly endless series of incidents
对于探员们只知使用武力 而不愿运用大脑一事
in which theJustice Department and the FBI have been questioned
司法部及调查局已受到质询
about their use of firepower rather than judgment.
这次的灾难是由调查局探员 史黛琳所引起
This time it was FBI Special Agent Clarice Starling heading up the calamitous strike force.
十年前 为了营救 前田纳西议员的女儿凯瑟琳
Agent Starling attained some measure of celebrity ten years ago
史黛琳曾经由"食人魔"汉尼拔医生的协助 得以破案
when she was given information by Dr. Hannibal "The Cannibal"Lecter which led to the rescue of Catherine Martin
她因此而声名大噪
daughter of the former US senator from Tennessee.
但是这个礼拜当她回复工作时 迎接她的不是表扬而是诉讼
When she returns to work this week, she won't be so celebrated.
因为代表被害家属的泰福律师 将控告她误杀至死之罪
Attorney Telford Higgins, representing one of the families of those slain says he will file a wrongful-death suit.
柯德!
Cordell!
-有什么吩咐  -替我接司法部
-Yes, sir. -Get me theJustice Department.
史黛琳探员?
Agent Starling?
这是禁药取缔局的约翰 助理执政官诺门
This is John Eldridge from DEA. Assistant Director Noonan, you know.
我们部门的拉金 他专精责任问题
Larkin Wayne from our Office of Professional Responsibility.
武器管制局的包勃
Bob Sneed, ATF.
市长助理班尼 还有司法部的保罗
Benny Holcombe, assistant to the mayor. And Paul Krendler.
你应该认识他
You know Paul. Paul's come over from Justice
他以非官方身份来协助我们
unofficially, as a favor to us.
换句话说 他并不在这里
In other words, he's here, and he's not here.
我想你已经看过 报纸和电视的报导吧
So I take it you've seen the coverage in the papers and on television?
那些新闻和我无关
I have nothing to do with the news, Mr. Krendler.
那个女人手中抱着婴儿
The woman had a baby in her arms.
照片就在这里 你应该知道问题有多严重
There are pictures. You could see the problem, I would think.
婴儿是在她胸前挂的婴儿袋里
Not in her arms. In a carrier across her chest.
她手里拿的是冲锋枪
In her arms she had a MAC-10.
我们是来帮你的
Look, we're here to help you, Starling.
你这样怒气冲冲的态度 只会使事情更难办
It's gonna be a hell of a lot harder to do with a combative attitude.
我能自由发言吗?
Can I speak freely, Mr. Pearsall?
我是应你们的要求 来协助做这次突击的
Your agency called this office to get me assigned to help you on this raid.
我的确尽力去做
I tried to do that.
但有人却不遵守我所做的判断
I clearly expressed my judgment and was ignored.
以致牺牲了一位好朋友探员
And now a good agent and a friend is dead.
别忘了你还杀了五个人
You shot and killed five people out there, Agent Starling.
难道能说这是好的判断吗?
Is that how you define good judgment?
这是一场丑恶的突击
This raid was an ugly mess.
我被迫在被杀
I ended up in a position where I had a choice of dying
或射杀身挂婴儿的女人中做选择
or shooting a woman carrying a child.
我做了选择
I chose.
就是射杀她
I shot her.
我杀了带着婴儿的母亲
I killed a mother holding her child.
我很后悔 也恨我自己
And I regret it. I resent myself for it.
对不起 现在要终止这个会议
Gentlemen, I'm going to call a halt to this meeting
我会个别打电话给你们
and get back to you individually by phone.
真会浪费时间
That was a waste of time.
史黛琳 你居然有秘密仰慕者
You have a secret admirer, Starling.
他本身不怎么样 却有身居高位的朋友
He isn't much to look at, but he does have friends in high places.
你记得马森维杰吗?
Remember Mason Verger?
汉尼拔的第四个被害人
Lecter's fourth victim.
他很富有
The rich one.
也是唯一死里逃生的人
The only one that survived.
他说有些汉尼拔的新资料 但是只愿意告诉你
He says he has some new information on Lecter he'll only share with you.
那是什么意思? 如有需要 就扣押文件呀
What do you mean, only share it with me? You want it, seize it.
-最好别这么做  -我并没有和你讲话
-I'd rather not. -I wasn't speaking to you.
当我和你讲话时 自然会看着你
When I speak to you, you'll know it because I'll look at you.
为什么不这么做?
Why would we rather not?
上次他因为我们把汉尼拔从 十大通缉犯中除去而打电话来
The last time he called was when we took Lecter off the Ten Most Wanted List.
他很生气 我们对他说"嘿 你最好接受"
He was upset about that. We said, "Hey, that's life."
他说:参议院的失察委员会"爱序山庄"
He said, "This is a Senate Oversight Committee
会给你们好看的
to make your life miserable."
他家族对政治上献金一向慷慨
His family's political contributions may not be enough
虽然买不起参议员
to buy a senator
但是绝对租得起
but they are enough to rent them from time to time.
况且他若真有线索 我们又何必惹他生气
There's no reason to go through that if he really does have something new.
史黛琳 其实这件事对你有利
It's a good deal for you, Starling. You can't pretend it isn't.
因为你能再回去侦办知名案件
Get to go back on a celebrated case.
媒体方面 我会替你去和他们交涉
I'll take care of the media for your Drumgo killing.
大家都高兴
Everyone's gonna be happy.
我并不高兴
I'm not happy.
也许你根本就不会高兴
Well, maybe you're incapable of being happy.
保罗先生
Mr. Krendler
我们都知道做为一个探员 随时都有死亡的危险
out on the street, you know you might take a bullet in the line of duty.
如果怕死 那就不要做
You accept it or you get out.
所以我们接受这个事实
You live with it.
但所不能接受的是
What you don't expect or accept
你按照所受过的训练 和上级的指示去做
is taking one in the back in your boss's office
而结果却背上黑锅
for doing your job exactly as they've taught you.
这才叫人气愤
That makes you unhappy.
史黛琳 你说得不错
Of course you're right, Starling
但毕竟改变不了什么
but it doesn't change anything.
它改变了一切 连我在内
It changes everything. It changes me.
嗨 我叫柯德 是维杰先生的私人医生
Hi, I'm Cordell Doemling, Mr. Verger's private physician.
你好
How do you do?
麻烦你把车停到那边
If you'd be so kind as to park down at the end.
希望你的眼睛能适应这个昏暗光线
One's eyes adjust to the darkness.
维杰先生 史黛琳探员来了
Mr. Verger, Agent Starling is here.
你早 维杰先生
Good morning, Mr. Verger.
你开的是福特野马吗?
Was that a Mustang I heard out there?
是的
Yes, it was.
5000c.c.的引擎?
Five-liter?
是的
Yes.
那好快呀
Fast.
柯德 你可以离开了
Cordell, I think you can leave us now.
如果我留下来可能会有用
I thought I might stay. Perhaps I could be useful.
你去看我的午餐准备得如何
You could be useful seeing about my lunch.
你不介意我把麦克风 夹在你的衣服或枕头上吧
I'll attach this microphone to your clothing or pillow, if that's okay.
不会的
By all means.
这样会比较容易些
Here, this should make it easier.
对发生在我身上的事
You know, I thank God
我必须感谢上帝
for what happened.
因为这是赎罪
It was my salvation.
史黛琳探员 你信主吗?
Have you accepted Jesus, Agent Starling?
-你有信仰吗?  -我家人信奉路德教派
-Do you have faith? -I was raised Lutheran.
那不是我问的问题
That's not what I asked.
这是5143690号史黛琳探员
This is Special Agent Clarice Starling, 5143690
我作证在三月二十日 维杰已经发誓会说实话
deposing Mason R. Verger on March 20, sworn and attested.
我想说我童年时代 在夏令营里的快乐时光
I want to tell you about summer camp. It was a wonderful childhood experience.
-等会儿再谈吧  -我现在就要说
-We can get to that later. -We can get to it now.
因为这些全有关联
You see, it all comes to bear.
那是在我父亲所创办的基督夏令营里
It was a Christian camp my father founded
它专门收容孤苦无依的孩子们
for poor, unfortunate, cast-off little boys and girls
为了一块糖 他们愿做任何事
who would do anything for a candy bar.
维杰先生 我对你的恋童癖不感兴趣
Mr. Verger, I don't need to know about the sex offenses.
没关系 在美国律师之前我已免疫
It's all right. I have immunity from the US Attorney.
甚至在上帝面前
And I have immunity
我也免疫了
from the risen Jesus.
因为没人禁得起巧克力糖的诱惑
And nobody beats the Riz.
在法院指派汉尼拔医生给你前 你是否已经认识他?
Had you ever seen Dr. Lecter before the court assigned you to him for therapy?
你指的是?
What do you mean?
社交上的认识?
Socially?
是的 你介意谈论它吗?
It is what I mean, yes, if you don't mind talking about it.
不会 我并不引以为耻
No, not at all. I'm not ashamed.
-我没这么说  -我们认识得很平常
-I didn't say you should be. -No, we met conventionally
是医师和病人的关系
as doctor and patient.
那他怎么会到你住处去?
How did he end up at your house?
当然是我邀他的罗
I invited him, of course
我邀他到我的临时住所去
to my pied-a-terre.
我穿着最诱人的衣服去开门
I came to the door in my nicest come-hither outfit.
因为我担心...
I was concerned...
他可能会怕我
that he'd be afraid of me.
但他似乎一点也不在乎
But he didn't seem to be afraid of me.
现在想起来是很可疑
That's almost funny now.
我把我的性玩具拿给他看
I showed him my toys
其中包括那套活结装置
my noose setup, among other things.
就是可以把自己吊起来 却又不会窒息的装置
It's where you sort of hang yourself, but not really.
那种感觉真好 如果...
It feels good while you...
反正你能想像得出来
well, you know.
总归...
Anyway...
-他说"维杰"  -维杰 要不要来点兴奋剂?
-he said, "Mason," -Mason, would you like a popper?
我说"哇!当然要"
And I said, "Would I? Oh, wow!"
药效出来后 我兴奋到极点
Once that kicked in, I was flying.
他说"让我看看你那种"
He said, "Mason, show me how you smile
"能赢得小孩信任的笑容"
to gain the confidence of a child."
当我笑起来时...
When I smiled...
他又说"我看出来 他们为什么会信任你"
he said, "Oh, I see how you do it."
医生手里拿着 镜子的碎片朝我走来
The good doctor approached me with a piece of broken mirror.
"试试用这个"
"Try this."
把你脸上的肉割下来
Try peeling off your face
然后拿去喂狗吃
And feeding it to the dogs.
不行 我还是看得到你的笑容
No, I can still see it.
再来一次
Try again.
还是不行
No, I'm afraid not.
那就是所谓的娱乐
That's entertainment
说实话 当时似乎觉得很好玩
Well, it seemed like a good idea at the time.
你提到最近又有新的线索
You indicated to me that you'd received some kind of new information.
柯德
Cordell.
这是怎么来的?
Where did this come from?
寄来的 两个星期前到的
Buenos Aires. I received it two weeks ago.
外面的信封呢?
Where's the package it came in?
问得好 上面并没有写什么重要的东西
Good question. There was nothing written on it of interest.
我们是不是扔了?
Did we throw it out?
是的 实在很抱歉
Yes, I'm afraid we did.
你看这个会有帮助吗?
Oh, dear. You think it'll help?
但愿如此
I hope so.
希望能帮你捉到他
I hope it'll help you catch him
以雪你这次不名誉的耻辱
to help cleanse the stigma of your recent dishonor.
谢谢你 我走了
Thank you. That's all I need.
当你在收容所 和汉尼拔医生谈话时
Did you find some rapport with Dr. Lecter
有没有对他产生信赖感?
in your talks at the asylum?
当我在割自己脸时 曾经有过那种感觉
I know I did while I was peeling.
我们是用文明的方法交换心得
We exchanged information in a civil way.
但还是隔着一层玻璃
But always through the glass.
是的
Yes.
-你很奇怪?  -为什么?
-Isn't it funny? -What's that?
你对我的脸无动于衷
You can look at my face
可是一听我提上帝 反儿使你胆怯
but you shied when I said the name of God.
-找到你要找的吗?  -你确定只有这些?
-Finding what you want? -Are you sure this is all of it?
到目前为止 只剩这些
That's all there is now.
本来不止的 可惜被人一点一点的拿走了
There was more, but it's been picked over little by little over the years.
这些东西在特定市场中 能值不少钱
You know, this stuff s worth a lot of money in certain circles.
就像这里的可卡因一样
It's kind of like the cocaine that disappears around here
一点一点的消失掉
little by little.
*巴尔的摩州立法医医院*
嘿 巴尼
Hey, Barney.
还记得我吗?
Remember me?
史黛琳探员 请你声明 你并没有把权益念给我听
Would you agree for the record, Agent Starling that I've not been read my rights?
我声明巴尼并不知道他的权益
I have not Mirandized Barney. He is unaware of his rights.
在你把汉尼拔医生 交给田纳西警局后
So when you turned Dr. Lecter over to the Tennessee police
他们对他无礼 如今都死了
They weren't civil to him. They're all dead now.
实际上他们只活了三天
They only survived his company three days.
但是你却活了六年
You survived him six years at the asylum.
你是怎么做到的? 我觉得这和礼貌无关
How'd you do that? It wasn't just being civil.
有很大的关系
Yes, it was.
在他逃走后 你有没有想过他可能来找你?
Did you ever think, after he escaped, he might come after you?
没有
No.
他曾对我说过在可能的情况下
He once told me that, whenever feasible
他宁愿吃无礼之人
he preferred to eat the rude.
他叫他们"无礼鼠类" 你呢?
"Free-range rude," he called 'em. What about you?
你有没有想过他 或想过他可能会来找你?
You ever think he might come after you? You ever think about him at all?
每天都会想上三十秒
At least 30 seconds of every day. I can't help it.
就像坏习惯一样 戒也戒不掉
He's always with me, like a bad habit.
他的东西 像书 纸 和图画等等都到哪里去了
Do you know what happened to his stuff  his books, papers, drawings?
收容所关闭时 所有的东西都丢了
Everything got thrown away when the place closed.
节省经费嘛
Cutbacks.
我发现由汉尼拔医生 签名的那本烹饪之乐杂志
I just found out that Dr. Lecter's signed copy of TheJoy of Cooking
最近被私人收藏家 以一万六千美金买进
sold to a private collector for $16,000.
恐怕是仿造品
It was probably a fake.
卖主切结书上的签名是 "费凯伦"
The seller's affidavit of ownership was signed "Karen Phlox."
你应该认识她
Do you know Karen Phlox? You should.
她曾替你填过工作申请表 最后签上"巴尼"
She filled out your employment application, but signed it "Barney."
还有退税单也一样
Same thing on your tax returns.
如果你要书 我会试着把它要回来
You want the book? Maybe I can get it back.
当他攻击护士时 你曾打断 他的手臂 我要那张X光片
I want the x-ray of Lecter's arm you broke in the attack on that nurse
还有其它被你拿走的东西
and everything else you've got.
在夜深人静 尖叫声平息之后
We used to talk about a lot of things at night
我们时常聊天
after the screamin' finally died down.
有时也谈到你 你想知道他都说些什么吗?
We talked about you sometimes. You wanna know what he said?
把X光片给我
Go get the x-ray.
我不是个坏人
I'm not a bad guy.
我没说你是坏人
I didn't say you were.
奇顿医生才是坏人
Dr. Chilton was a bad guy.
在你第一次访问汉尼拔医生后 他就开始录你们的谈话
After your first visit, he started taping your conversations with Lecter.
它们非常有价值
These are valuable.
你走吧
Go on now.
你已经哀吊得够久了
You've grieved long enough.
他是怎么说的?
And what'd he say?
在晚上他怎么说我的?
What'd he say about me late at night?
他谈到遗传和内心深处的行为
He was talking about inherited, hardwired behavior.
他用鹞鸽的遗传来做比方
He was using genetics in the roller pigeons as an example.
它们喜欢高高的飞到天上 然后炫耀的翻着筋斗俯冲下来
They fly up in the air, roll backwards in a display, fallin' to the ground.
鹞鸽分为肤浅和深沉两种
There are shallow rollers, and there are deep rollers.
但是当两只深沉鹞鸽结合后
You can't breed two deep rollers
它们的后代往往会
or their young, their offspring, will roll all the way down
俯冲撞地而死
hit and die.
巴尼 史黛琳探员是只深沉的鹞鸽
Agent Starling is a deep roller, Barney.
只希望她父母中有一个是只肤浅的鹞鸽
Let us hope one of her parents was not.
你并没有离开正轨
Surely the odd confluence of events hasn't escaped you, Clarice.
因为杰克在我面前向你挑战
Jack Crawford dangles you in front of me
所以我才给你一些帮助
then I give you a bit of help.
难道你以为是因为...
Do you think it's because I like to look at you...
我喜欢边看你边想着你会有多可口吗?
and imagine how good you would taste
真是这样吗?
Clarice?
我不知道 难道是真的?
I don't know. Is it?
我待在这个房间里已经八年
I've been in this room for eight years now, Clarice.
我知道在我有生之年 他们是不会让我出去的
I know they will never, ever let me out while I'm alive.
我只想能看外面的风景
What I want is a view.
给我一扇窗户 让我能看到树甚至河流
I want a window where I can see a tree or even water.
我想转到联邦收容所去 那样才能远离奇顿医生
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton.
卡波尼图书馆中的书信 可以追溯到十三世纪
The Capponi correspondence goes back to the 13th century.
至于在费尔博士手中
Dr. Fell might hold in his hand
他那非意大利人的手中
his non-Italian hand
很可能握有但丁的真迹
a note from Dante Alighieri himself.
但是他能分辨出真伪吗? 我不认为
But would he recognize it? I think not.
各位 你们已经肯定 他对意大利中叶的辨认能力
Gentlemen, you have examined him in medieval Italian
我也承认对一个外国人来说
and I will not deny that his language is admirable
他的文字实在美妙
for a straniero.
但是他是否真正具有 文艺复兴前佛罗伦斯的气质
But is he acquainted with the personalities of the pre-Renaissance Firenze?
我却有所怀疑
I think not.
说不定哪天在卡波尼图书馆中
What if he came upon a note in the Capponi library
他会声称找到了 诗人卡瓦澄第的真迹
say from Guido di Cavalcanti?
难道他真能分辨出真伪吗? 我不相信
Would he recognize that? I think not.
他们还在争论吗?
They're still arguing?
苏立想让他侄子做这份工作
Sogliato wants the job for his nephew.
可是学者们似乎对 他们所指定的人很满意
But the scholars seem satisfied with the temporary guy they appointed.
倘若他真那么精通但丁
If he's such an expert on Dante
为何不让他 发表一场对但丁研究的演讲
let him lecture on Dante to the Studiolo.
-好面对但丁的爱好者  -好主意
-Let him face them if he can. -I look forward to it.
那就订在十四号好了
Very well. On the 14th.
费尔博士吗?
Dr. Fell?
我叫帕齐 是警察总部的督察
Chief Inspector Rinaldo Pazzi of the questura.
督察 我能帮什么忙?
Commendatore, how can I be of service?
抱歉 我在调查前任馆长 辛诺的失踪案件
Sorry. I'm investigating the disappearance of your predecessor, Signor di Bonaventura.
-不知道是否...  -你这么说 好像我已做了馆长
-I was wondering if...  -"Predecessor" implies I have the job.
我是希望如此 可惜他们还没决定
Unfortunately, I don't. Not yet, though I am hopeful.
他们只是支薪给我 让我照顾图书馆而已
They are letting me look after the library for a stipend.
以前的调查员
The officers who first checked
没有找到遗书或自杀信
didn't find any sort of farewell or suicide note.
希望你能...
I was wondering if you...
如果我在抽屉或书中 找到任何有用的东西
If I come across anything in the Capponi library stuffed in a drawer or book
一定会立刻通知你
I'll call you at once.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你被改派任务了
You've been reassigned.
你说什么?
Pardon?
我记得 你本来在调查莫斯楚的案件
You were on the II Mostro case, I'm sure I read.
-没错  -现在却查这个案子
-Yes, that's right. -Now you're on this.
就我所知 这不是什么大案子
This is much less grand a case, I would think.
如果以知名度而言...
Well, if I thought of my work in those terms
你说的不错
yes, I guess I'd agree.
-调查失踪人口  -你说什么?
-A missing person. -Sorry?
是因为不平等待遇 还是因为你的能力不够?
Were you unfairly dismissed from the grander case, or did you deserve it?
费尔博士 让我们再回到原题
Regarding this one, Dr. Fell
辛诺的私人物品 是否仍在图书馆内?
are the signore's personal effects still at the Palazzo?
一共装了四大箱 还有清单
Packed neatly in four cases with an inventory.
就是没有遗书
Alas, no note.
我会叫人来取 谢谢你的帮忙
I'll send someone over to pick them up. Thank you for your help.
嘿 谢谢你
Hey, thanks.
进行的如何?有线索吗?
How's it going? Any leads?
都是线索 可惜就是找不到他
Yeah, they're all leads. They just don't lead to him.
真佩服你能天天和这些为伍
I don't know how you live with this stuff.
天呀
Oh, God.
这封是世界记录给我的恭贺函
This is from the Guinness Book of World Records congratulating me
说我创下 女调查员中杀人最多的记录
on being the female FBI agent who has shot and killed the most people.
能不能请你离开一下
Would you excuse me, please?
没问题
Sure.
亲爱的史黛琳
Dear Clarice
我认真追踪你这次的受辱事件
I've followed with enthusiasm the course of your disgrace and public shaming.
我对自己的受辱并不在乎
My own never bothered me except for the inconvenience
只对失去自由有所不满
of being incarcerated.
但你的眼界 却让我操心
But you may lack perspective.
从我们在地牢中的讨论中
In our discussions down in the dungeon
我发现 你那位做守夜员的父亲
it was apparent to me that your father, the dead night watchman
在你心目中占有很重的份量
figures largely in your value system.
当初你最得意 能将杰姆绳之以法
I think your success in putting an end toJame Gumb's career as a couturier
因为你觉得 那会使你父亲引以为傲
pleased you most because you could imagine your father being pleased.
可惜如今你却成了 调查局中的老鼠屎
But now, alas, you're in bad odor with the FBI.
"调查局探员枪杀五人" 你父亲会不会因此
Do you imagine your daddy being shamed by your disgrace?
而感到丢脸
Do you see him in his plain pine box
他是否会躺在棺材中 眼见你手刃这份前途无量的工作
crushed by your failure
而痛心疾首吗?
the sorry, petty end of a promising career?
这份耻辱最大的影响是什么?
What is worst about this humiliation, Clarice?
是因为你的失败 会影响到你父母的形象?
Is it how your failure will reflect on your mommy and daddy?
还是你害怕从此以后...
Is your worst fear that people will now and forever believe
人们认为他们只是 住在活动房屋中...
they were indeed just good old trailer-camp
没用的穷白鬼
tornado-bait white trash
而你也和他们一样?
and that perhaps you are too?
顺便一提 我发现在调查局的网页上
By the way, I couldn't help noticing on the FBI's rather dull web site
我居然从普通罪犯
that I've been hoisted from the Bureau's archives of the common criminal
升级到十大通缉犯
and elevated to the more prestigious Ten Most Wanted List.
是巧合 还是你又开始侦办我的案件?
Is this coincidence, or are you back on the case?
果真如此 那好 我将从退隐的地方走出
If so, goody goody, because I need to come out of retirement
再回到公众的生活中去
and return to public life.
我可以想像出 你正坐在黯淡的地下室里
I imagine you sitting in a dark basement room
埋首于纸堆和电脑荧光幕中
bent over papers and computer screens.
我说对了吧
Is that accurate?
史黛琳探员 请告诉我实话
Please tell me truly, Special Agent Starling.
请珍重 你的老友 汉尼拔医生
Regards, your old pal, Hannibal Lecter, MD.
附注 我看得出这不是你的本意
PS: Clearly this new assignment is not your choice.
可能是某种交换
Rather, I suppose, it is part of the bargain.
可是你仍然接受了
But you accepted it, Clarice.
你的职责是毁灭我
Yourjob is to craft my doom
所以实在不知道 在信尾该怎么祝你
so I'm not sure how well I should wish you
不过我相信 我们将会有很多乐趣
but I'm sure we'll have a lot of fun.
回见
Ta-ta.
"汉"
"H."
在信上
On the letter
找到一个局部的指纹
there's one partial fingerprint here.
-可是在法庭上还嫌不够  -这一定是他
-Not enough to hold up in court. -I know it's him.
我只想知道他在哪里写这封信
Where he was when he wrote it is what I need.
可惜从信纸上看不出来
Well, the paper isn't gonna help.
其中有亚麻纤维的成份 应该属于奢侈品
Yes, it's linen fibre, yes, it's on the expensive side
但是却不罕见 全球至少 有上千家店会卖这种信纸
but it's not so rare that you won't find it in a thousand stationery stores throughout the world.
至于墨水和腊也是一样
It's the same with the ink, and the same with the wax.
还有拉斯维加斯的邮戳
And your Las Vegas postmark?
我跟你打赌 是由重寄邮件服务公司寄的
You can check it out, but I'll bet you it came from a remailing service.
看来赌城是他最后的停留点
Las Vegas would be the last place he'd be.
他的品味不该这么低
It'd be an assault on his sense of taste.
难道你不觉得 有目光在你身上游动吗?
Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice?
你当然会感觉得到
I hardly see how you couldn't.
人的眼光 会在喜欢的东西上游走
And don't your eyes move over the things you want?
告诉我是怎么回事
All right, then. Tell me how.
不
No.
现在轮到你告诉我了
It's your turn to tell me, Clarice.
难道你想再骗我到那个 布满动物传染病的岛上去?
You don't have any more vacations to sell on Anthrax Island.
别忘了我们这是公平交易
Quid pro quo, Clarice.
我告诉你一件事 你也得告诉我一件事
I tell you things, you tell me things.
不谈案子 就说你自己吧
Not about this case. About yourself.
这就是公平交易
Quid pro quo.
史黛琳 你愿意吗?
Yes or no, Clarice?
手霜
Hand cream.
其中有龙涎香
Raw ambergris base.
田纳西的熏衣草
Tennessee lavender.
还有一些别的东西
Trace of something else.
羊毛
Fleece.
不错
Lovely.
-龙涎香是什么东西?  -它来自鲸鱼
-What's ambergris? -Ambergris is a whale product.
虽然我们也喜欢但不准进口
Alas, much as we'd like to, we can't import it.
因为这会危害到稀有动物
Endangered Species Act.
-在哪些国家是合法呢?  -毫无疑问的是日本
-Where isn't it illegal? -Japan, of course.
另外还有一些欧洲国家
Couple of places in Europe.
我肯定在巴黎 罗马 阿姆斯特丹可以找到
You'd almost certainly find it somewhere in Paris,Rome,Amsterdam.
伦敦也有可能
Maybe London.
这种香味 是照客人的指示以手工合成的
This bouquet was hand-engineered to someone's specifications.
-能知道是出自哪个商店吗?  -可以 我们会给你一张名单
-Is there a way of knowing which shops? -Of course. We'll give you a list.
放心 不会太长
It'll be short.
我需要歌剧票
I need opera tickets.
我身上没有了
I don't think I got any on me.
换句话说是卖光了
It's sold out, whatever it's called.
是他那个年轻漂亮的太太 吵着要去看歌剧
It's the pretty, young wife with the ever-open beak who needs opera tickets.
-班尼第  -什么事?
-Benetti. -What?
倒带
Rewind it.
不行 我正在拷贝
I can't rewind it. I'm making a copy. I'm recording.
这是什么带子?
What is this?
是位在斯卡拉大道上 香水店的防盗录影带
Security camera from a perfume shop in Via Della Scala.
美国调查局经由国际刑警组 向我们要求的
FBI, through Interpol, requested a copy.
-为什么?  -他们没说
-Why? -They didn't say.
-没说?  -他们的态度很奇怪
-They didn't say? -No. It was actually kind of weird.
摆明了不告诉我们
They were making a point not to say.
*调查局探员史黛琳*
*联邦调查局*
*调查局十大在逃通缉犯*
*暴戾罪犯的逮捕计划*
*警告 你正企图进入联邦情报局的资料库*
-我们仍要去听歌剧吗?  -是的
-Are we going to the opera? -Yes.
对不起 当然要去
Sorry. Yes, we are going.
买到票了吗?
You got tickets?
还没有 我正要上网查看 一定会买到
No, but I will. In fact, I was just about to look here.
拜托别买得太后面 否则又看不到
Please, not the back row. I would like to see it this time.
绝对不会
Nowhere near the back row
这次不管多贵也要买前座
no matter what the cost.
*登入*
*调查局十大在逃通缉犯*
*携带武器并且极度危险*
*汉尼拔悬赏金*
*搜寻*
*找到一个汉尼拔悬赏金*
*逮捕汉尼拔归案的悬赏金*
*汉尼拔曾是一位 出色的精神科医生*
*在1990年逃逸之后 成为搜索的焦点*
*三百万的赏金将付给 能提供线索使他归案的人*
*想提供汉尼拔线索的人 请打1-212-555-0118*
史黛琳 你有没有想过
Tell me, Clarice, would you want to harm
去伤害那些迫害过你的人?
those who forced you to consider it, though?
你尽管承认
It's perfectly okay to admit it.
因为想向敌人挑战
It's perfectly au naturel
那是人性自然的表现
to want to taste the enemy.
它会使你感到愉快
It just feels so good. Tell me, Clarice.
什么是你童年中 最不快乐的记忆?
What is your worst memory of childhood?
-你吓了我一大跳  -需要我帮忙吗?
-Jesus, Starling! -Can I help you, Mr. Krendler?
一个人坐在黑暗中干什么?
What are you doing sitting there in the dark?
正想着吃人的问题
Thinking about cannibalism.
司法部也在思索这个问题 你知道吗?
People in Justice are thinking too. You know that?
他们在想"她到底想对 汉尼拔采取什么手段"
They're thinking, " What exactly is she doing about Lecter?"
你对他爱吃人是否感到好奇?
Aren't you curious why he dines on his victims?
这话是什么意思?
What's the point of that?
你到底是想写小说 还是想捉贼?
Are you writing a book or are you catching a crook?
为了报复那些侮辱他的人
To show his contempt for those who exasperate him.
所以他才偶尔充当刽子手
Or sometimes to perform a public service.
就拿横笛手班哲明为例
In the case of the flutist, Benjamin Raspail
由于他供应小牛胰脏 和七百美金一瓶的蒙哈榭白酒
he did it to improve the sound of the Baltimore Philharmonic Orchestra
给乐团中那些 没什么天份的横笛手享用
serving the not-so-talented flute player's sweetbreads to the board
因而使 巴尔的摩交响乐团的声名大噪
with a nice Montrachet at $700 a bottle.
哇!
Wow.
那顿饭的开胃菜是 产自法国隆特的牡蛎
That meal began with green oysters from the Gironde
接着是小牛胰脏 果汁奶冻
followed by the sweetbreads, a sorbet
其他的你可以看这本美食杂志
and then you can read here in Gourmet Cuisine:
"有名的黑且光泽的 蔬菜炖肉 其中材料不明"
"A notable dark and glossy ragout, the constituents never determined."
我一直认为他有同性恋
I always figured him for a queer.
为什么你会这么想?
Why would you say that, Paul?
因为他搞的 全是艺术方面的事
All this artsy-fartsy stuff.
像音乐室 茶会美食之类的 不是我多事...
Chamber music, tea-party food. Not that I mean anything personal
我觉得你似乎很同情那种人
if you've got a lot of sympathy for those people.
我来这里是想让你明白
What I came to impress upon you, Starling
最好乖乖合作
is I better see cooperation.
这案子不是你一个人的
There are no little fiefdoms here.
你必须随时向我报告进展 懂吗?
I want to be copied on every 302, you understand?
好好和我合作
If you work with me
那么你所谓的前途就会无量
then your so-called career here might improve.
否则 我不但不在你名字下划线
If you don't, then all I have to do
反而把线从你名字中间划过去
is draw a line through your name rather than under it
那你就前途无亮啦
and it's over.
你到底想怎么样?
Paul, what is it with you?
我叫你回到你太太身边去 难道错了吗?
I told you to go home to your wife. That was wrong?
拜托 你少自做多情了
What? Don't flatter yourself, Starling.
那是几百年前的事
That was a long time ago.
我才不会记那么久的仇
Why would I hold that against you?
加上...
And besides...
这个城里到处都是 种田的乡下女人
this town is full of corn pone, country pussy.
换句话说...
That said...
如果你愿意 我现在就能奉陪
I wouldn't mind having a go with you right now, if you want to reconsider.
我随时在拳击场候教 来场不穿保护衣的对打
In the gym, anytime. No pads.
会不会是用普通邮件送出的?
Is it possible it went out with the regular mail?
不会 是我亲手填的快递单
No, I overnighted it to you. I filled out the slip myself.
而且在你委托的第二天就寄了
This was the day after your request.
我实在想不通
I did it right away. I don't understand what happened.
你现在该收到了
You should have it by now.
还没有 能不能请你再寄一份
I don't. Can you send me another one?
没问题 我会特别替你再录一份
Sure, I'll make another copy especially for you.
是克莉丝探员吗? 我能叫你克莉丝吗?
Agent Clarice? Is that right? Can I call you Clarice?
请叫我史黛琳探员
Agent Starling.
谢谢你的帮忙 请问贵姓?
I'd appreciate it. What's your name?
我叫班尼帝
My name is Franco Benetti.
班尼帝探员
Agent Franco Benetti.
-非常谢谢你 班尼帝探员  -不客气
-Thank you very much, Agent Benetti. -Okay.
-那我明天就寄给你  -好的
-So I'll send you tomorrow? -All right.
再见
Bye-bye.
还是没有线索?
Nothin', huh?
没有 我还在等 佛罗伦斯和伦敦的录影带
Nothin' yet. Still waitin' on Florence and London.
你所拨的号码已停止使用
The number you have dialed is not in service at this time.
请检查所拨的号码...
Please check the number...
什么事?
Yes?
我有汉尼拔的消息
I have information about Hannibal Lecter.
请问你是否和警方联络过?
Have you shared your information with the police, sir?
我鼓励你先这么做
I'm required to encourage you to do so.
在哪种情况下才会付悬赏金
Is the reward payable under special circumstances?
我建议你在采取行动之前
May I suggest you contact an attorney
先和律师联络一下
before taking any possibly illegal action?
在日内瓦有个律师 专精这种案件
There's one in Geneva who's excellent in these matters.
我可以给你他的免费电话
May I give you his toll-free number?
号码是004123317
The number is 004123317.
谢谢你打电话过来
Thank you for calling.
有人向我建议
Yes. I was just speaking with someone who suggested
预付金是十万美金
There's a $ 100,000 advance.
为了符合预付金的条件
To qualify for the advance
必须先提供目标物的真实指纹
a fingerprint must be provided, in situ, on an object.
等身份证实无误后
Once the print has been positively identified
即将余款存入瑞士银行
the balance of the money will be placed in escrow
交由代书保管
at Geneve Credit Suisse
你可以随时检验 只要在24小时前通知即可
and may be viewed at any time subject to 24-hour prior notification.
听法文请按二
To repeat the message in French, press two.
西班牙文请按三 德文...
In Spanish, press three. In German...
费尔博士 我是帕齐督察
Dr. Fell, it's Inspector Pazzi.
是的 我看得见你
Yes, I can see you.
请上来
Come on up.
费尔博士?
Dr. Fell?
照张相
Snap.
我应该嘱咐你多带个人来
I should have encouraged you to bring someone along.
箱子很重
The cases are on the heavy side.
也许要请你帮忙
Maybe you could help me with them.
只要搬到楼下就好
Just down the stairs, I mean.
好的
Yeah.
这边走
This way.
就在这儿
Here we are.
-那是清单吗?  -是的
-Is that the inventory? -Yes.
-我能看吗?  -当然可以
-May I see it? -Of course.
你应该是帕齐家族之后
You are a Pazzi of the Pazzi family, I think.
在维琪奥王宫被吊死的 就是你的祖先
Wasn't it at the Palazzo Vecchio your ancestor was hanged?
他叫范斯库帕齐
Francesco de' Pazzi.
脖子上绑着套索 裸体从窗口中被抛出去
Yes, thrown naked with a noose around his neck from a window.
在大主教的身边
Writhing and kicking alongside the archbishop
碰撞着冰冷的墙壁 全身扭动挣扎而死
against the cold stone wall.
前几天 我在图书馆中
In fact, I found a very nice rendering of it
找到了相关的艺术文献
here in the library the other day.
如果你喜欢 我可以偷偷给你
If you like, perhaps I could sneak it out for you.
这么做的话...
I would think that might jeopardize your chances
可能会影响到你做馆长的机会
for permanent appointment to the curatorship.
除非你去告密
Only if you told.
他到底犯了什么罪?
Remind me  what was his crime?
他被控杀死朱利亚诺梅迪奇
He was accused of killing Giuliano de' Medici.
不公正吗?
Unjustly?
不 应该是公正的
No, I don't think so.
那么说来 他是罪有应得
Then he wasn't just accused. He did it. He was guilty.
我想就算在五百年后的今天
I think that would make living in Florence with the name Pazzi
你仍会为 祖先的罪行而感到困扰
uncomfortable, even 500 years later.
这倒不会
Not really.
其实在今天之前
In fact, I can't remember the last time
除了你根本就没人提过
before today someone brought it up.
通常人们 不会把他的想法说出来
People don't always tell you what they're thinking.
只是会确实做到
They just see to it you don't
不让你出人头地而已
advance in life.
对不起 请别介意
I'm sorry, Commendatore.
我常想什么 就说什么
I too often say what I'm thinking.
我马上就回来帮你搬
I'll be right back to help you.
你所待的房间 是建造在十五世纪
You know, the room you're standing in was built in the 15th century.
很美!
It's beautiful.
的确不错
Yes, it is.
只可惜 我在想...
Unfortunately, I think...
暖气系统 可能也是那时候建造的
the heating system was installed about the same time.
-那真不幸  -的确
-That's a pity. -Yes.
好吧 咱们把它们拿下去
Okeydokey. Let's drag these down.
这大概和尸体一样重
Must be as heavy as bodies.
-这一套多少钱?  -八千里拉
-And the set? -Eight thousand.
好
Okay.
喂 这个要多少钱?
Hey, how much is this?
-五万里拉  -我买了
-Fifty thousand. -I'll take it.
干得不错嘛
Well done.
当你要偷他的皮夹时 他就会握住你的手腕
When you go for his wallet, he'll catch you by the wrist.
督察 这种事我干过好几次
I have done this a few times, Inspector.
这次不一样
Not like this.
如果手镯上没有清晰的指纹
If there isn't a clean print on the bracelet
那么整个夏天 就请你到牢里去乘凉
you'll spend the summer in a cell at the Sollicciano.
把手镯给我
Give me the bracelet.
先把你的脏手洗干净
Wash your fucking hands.
他来啦
He's coming.
我弄到指纹了
I got it.
他正好握住手镯
He grabbed me just right.
居然想攻击我的下体
Tried to hit me in the balls.
可惜没成功
But he missed.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
不要
No. Don't.
维杰先生 一共有十六处相符
Sixteen-point match, Mr. Verger.
是他没错
Bingo.
*撒丁尼亚岛*
-是卡罗吗?  -维杰?
-Carlo? -Mason?
都很好
Well, well, well.
-要我去你那儿吗?  -应该快了
-Am I coming to see you? -Yes, soon, I hope.
不过你先把野猪运过来
But first I need you to pack off the boys.
-现在?  -是的 我知道
-Now? -Yes, I know.
你以为这一天永远不会来 对不对?
The day you never thought would arrive has.
柯德会直接把兽医表格
Now, Cordell will fax the veterinary forms
传真给动植物防疫检疫局
directly to Animal and Plant Health
但是你必须拿到 撒丁尼亚岛的兽医检验表
but you need to get the vet affidavits from Sardinia.
它们如何?
How are they?
越长越大 非常庞大
They are big, Mason, very big.
-你再说一次  -它们长得很大
-Say again? -Yeah, they are big, Mason.
大概有270公斤
Really big. Maybe 270 kilos.
哇!那么大
Oh, wow.
你听到了吗?
Can you hear?
听起来很强壮
They sound fantastic.
太好了
Super.
在收到活的汉尼拔医生后 余款就会全数付给你
The full balance of the money is payable upon receipt of the doctor, alive.
你该不会想自己去抓吧
Of course, you won't have to seize him yourself.
只要把他指认出来就行
Rather, just point him out.
其余的由我们来处理
It's preferable to all concerned if that's the extent of your involvement
这样对你会比较好
from this point.
我希望能一直参与下去 好确定不出问题
I prefer to stay involved, make sure things go right.
那将会由专家来执行
Professionals will see to that.
我就是专家
I am a professional.
督察 你对这场演出满意吗?
Did you enjoy the performance, Commendatore?
很满意
Very much.
艾葛莉 这位是费尔博士 卡波尼图书馆的馆长
Allegra, this is Dr. Fell, curator of the Capponi Library.
帕齐夫人
Signora Pazzi.
很荣幸见到你
I'm honored.
你来自美国吗?
Are you from America, Doctor?
我曾到过美国 但祖籍不是那里
Not originally. I've travelled there.
我一直想去新英格兰
I've always wanted to visit. New England, especially.
那里的食物非常可口
I've enjoyed many excellent meals there.
我注意到你对歌词很有兴趣
I noticed you wrapped up in the libretto.
相信你会喜欢这个
Thought this might amuse you.
这是但丁新生命中的 第一首十四行诗
Dante's first sonnet from La Vita Nuova.
对 它非常美妙
It's beautiful.
-帕齐 你来看  -我看到了
-Rinaldo, look at this. -I can see.
"对我来说喜悦的爱是"
"Joyous Love seemed to me
"当他手中捧着我的心"
the while he held my heart in his hands
"而在他臂弯中"
and in his arms
"却是我深爱的女士"
my lady lay asleep
"正裹着面纱沉睡着"
wrapped in a veil."
"然后他唤醒她"
"He woke her then
"她颤抖而顺从的 吃下他手中灼热的心"
and trembling and obedient, she ate that burning heart out of his hand.
"我哽咽的看着他逐渐远去"
Weeping, I saw him then depart from me."
费尔博士 你相信男人 在第一次和女人相遇后
Dr. Fell, do you believe a man could become so obsessed with a woman
就会迷上她吗?
from a single encounter?
他因此而寝食难安
Could he daily feel a stab of hunger for her
只有在见到她后才能平静?
and find nourishment in the very sight of her?
我相信
I think so.
但是她会看出他的苦境 而深深为他心痛吗?
But would she see through the bars of his plight and ache for him?
-这是送给你的  -我不能接受
-Please keep that. -I couldn't.
我坚持
I insist.
督察
Commendatore
艾葛莉
Allegra
再会
再见
Good-bye.
-我们去吃点东西吧  -好的
-Let's get something to eat. -Of course.
好主意?
Why not?
*使用者名称 密码*
*暴戾罪犯的逮捕计划*
*汉尼拔 登入系统者名单*
*期间 50天内*
医生 这会是你吗?
Is that you, Doctor?
请帕齐督察接电话
I'd like to speak with Chief Inspector Rinaldo Pazzi, please.
我是美国调查局探员史黛琳
This is Agent Clarice Starling from the American FBI.
请等一下
One moment.
帕齐
Pazzi.
-美国调查局的电话  -说我不在
-FBI. -I'm not here.
我是帕齐督察
Inspector Pazzi.
我是调查局的史黛琳探员 你好?
It's Agent Starling from the FBI. How do you do?
我现在正准备离开
Actually, I was just leaving for the day.
-明天再和你联络 好吗?  -不会耽误很久
-Can I call you back tomorrow? -This won't take long.
首先 谢谢你们寄给我 香水店的防盗录影带
First, thank you for sending us the security tape from the perfume store.
我指的是 由班尼帝探员寄来的带子
When I say "you,"I mean your department  Agent Benetti.
他在吗?我想和他谈谈
Is he there? Can I speak with him?
-抱歉 他已经走了  -那没关系
-I'm sorry. He's gone home. -That's all right.
其实我本就该对你说的
I should tell you this rather than him anyway.
我有个重要约会就要迟到了
I'm late for an important appointment.
我所要寻找的人
The person I'm looking for, Inspector
就出现在那个录影带里 他的名字是汉尼拔
who is indeed shown on that tape, is Hannibal Lecter.
谁?
Who?
汉尼拔医生 你没听过他吗?
Dr. Hannibal Lecter. You've never heard of him?
-我不是很清楚  -录影带中显示
-I'm not familiar. -And the tape confirms
他曾在佛罗伦斯出现过
that he is or was recently in Florence.
-是吗?  -督察 他非常危险
-Really? -He's a very dangerous man, Inspector.
已经杀害十四个人
He's killed 14 people that we know of.
-我得走了 你是...  -我叫史黛琳
-I really have to go, Miss...  -Starling.
再给我一分钟
Just another minute.
-你确定没听过他吗?  -我确定
-You sure you've never heard of him? -No, I haven't.
那就奇怪了
Because I'm confused.
因为根据资料显示 你们有人 时常使用电脑
Someone there has been accessing our private VICAP files on Dr. Lecter
从我们网站的VICAP档案中 存取汉尼拔医生的资料
with some regularity on your computer.
警局的电脑是公用的
Everybody uses everybody's computer here.
也许是侦办莫斯楚的警探
Maybe one of the detectives on II Mostro
上网查看杀人魔的资料
was looking at profiles of killers
我所说的是你家里的电脑
I'm speaking about the computer at your home, sir.
你是不是想自己去捉拿他 好拿悬赏金?
You're trying to catch him yourself, aren't you? For the reward.
我必须警告你千万别这么做
I cannot warn you strongly enough against that.
当他在曼非斯被监管时 曾杀了三名警员
He killed three policemen down in Memphis while in custody
其中之一的脸被他整个撕裂 他也会杀你的
tearing the face off one of them, and he will kill you too.
-我要他尽快离开此地  -相信我
-I want him out of Tuscany fast. -Believe me
他很快就会从地球上消失
he'll be gone from the face of the earth fast.
到棺材里去休息
Feetfirst.
由于他的贪婪 背判了信任他的国王
Because of his avarice and his betrayal of the emperor's trust
使得韦格那遭到贬黜 失明和下狱之殃
Pier della Vigna was disgraced, blinded and imprisoned.
但丁神曲把他放在地狱篇的 第七层地狱中
Dante's pilgrim finds Pier della Vigna on the seventh level of the Inferno
就像耶稣的叛徒犹大一样 被处以绞刑
and, likeJudas Iscariot, he died by hanging.
由此我们看出是贪婪
SoJudas and Pier della Vigna are linked in Dante
使但丁把他们俩连系起来
by the avarice he saw in them.
事实上 在中世纪时 贪婪和绞刑常连为一体
In fact, avarice and hanging are linked in the medieval mind.
最早的文献可见于西元400年 被刻在高卢的象牙盒上
This is the earliest known depiction of the Crucifixion
记录着有关耶稣被钉死在 十字架上的故事
carved on an ivory box in Gaul about A.D. 400.
其中包括绞杀犹大
It includes the death by hanging ofJudas
他的脸孔朝上 面对着吊死他的树枝
his face upturned to the branch that suspends him.
这个在 班尼文多大教堂门上的也是他
Here he is again on the doors of the Benevento Cathedral
不同的是 这里的他内脏外溢
this time with his bowels falling out.
请你听我说 我好不容易才要到你的号码
It wasn't easy, but I got this number without tellin'them why
-对不起  -没关系 欢迎你来
-Sorry. -Not at all. Welcome.
-请坐  -谢谢你
-Please join us. -Thank you.
这幅是十五世纪地狱篇的画
On this plate from the 15th-century edition of the Inferno
我们看到韦格那的尸体 挂在流着鲜血的树上
Pier della Vigna's body hangs from a bleeding tree.
我不想强调他和犹大的相似处
I will not belabor the obvious parallel with Judas Iscariot
因为但丁已经描述得很清楚
but Dante Alighieri needed no drawn illustration.
他技巧的表现出 韦格那仍在地狱之中
It was his genius to make Pier della Vigna, now in hell
声嘶力竭的喊叫和挣扎
speak in strained hisses and coughing sibilants
就像他仍被吊着一样
as though he is hanging still.
贪婪 绞刑
Avarice, hanging
自我毁灭
self-destruction.
"绞架"
"I make my own home
"就是我的家"
be my gallows."
今天到此为止 谢谢各位的光临
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for your kind attention.
我虽然不是学者 但相信你一定能当上馆长
I'm not a scholar, but I think you've got the job.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-我能请你去喝杯酒吗?  -这是我的荣幸
-May I buy you a drink? -How kind of you. I'd like that.
等我把东西收好就走
I'll be a minute gathering my things.
慢慢来
Take your time.
艾葛莉 我会晚点回家
Allegra, I'll be home just a little later than I said.
我和费尔博士去喝杯酒
I'm taking Dr. Fell out for a drink.
我看到很多人走出来
I can see the people coming out now.
很好 等会儿见 是我太太
Yes. Bye, honey. My wife.
是的
Of course.
刚才该给他们看这一张
I should have shown them this one.
怎么会忘了 记得我曾对你说过吗?
I can't imagine how I missed it. Remember? I told you about it.
那是我在图书馆里找到的
It's a rendering I found in the Capponi Library.
你能看得到吗?
Can you make it out?
那里有个名字
There's a name there
我曾对你提起过
the one I told you about.
他就是你的祖先
It's your ancestor, Commendatore
被吊死在这个窗子下面
hanging beneath these very windows.
范斯库帕齐
Francesco de' Pazzi.
另外我想向你坦白
On a related subject, I must confess to you
我正在认真的考虑
I'm giving very serious thought
拿你太太当晚餐
to eating your wife.
如果你能诚实回答我的问题
If you tell me what I need to know, Commendatore
或许到时会放她一马
it might be convenient for me to leave Florence without my meal.
我先来问你 然后再做决定 可以吗?
So I'll ask you the questions, and then we'll see. All right?
好吗?
Okay?
好
So.
你把我出卖给维杰吗?
Now, is it Mason Verger you sold me to?
别挣扎
No, no.
是眨两次眼 不眨一次
Blink twice for yes, once for no.
你把我出卖给维杰吗?
Was it Mason Verger you sold me to?
是 很好 谢谢你
Yes, good. Thank you.
他的人在外面等我吗?
And are his men waiting for me outside?
那是一下吗?
Was that a single blink?
你搞混了
You're confused.
别乱搅和 否则我真会把 帕齐夫人的肉片下来吃
Please don't be confused, because I may have to fillet Signora Pazzi after all.
你告诉过警局里的人吗?
Have you told anyone in the questura about me?
不 我也这么想
No, I thought not.
有没有告诉过你太太?
Have you told Allegra?
不 你确定
No? Are you sure?
我相信你
I believe you.
好吧 咱们可以开始了
Okeydokey, here we go.
好
Okay.
你的心抖得真厉害
Your heart is really palpitating.
原来不是你的心
Oh, it's not your heart.
我能回答吗?
Shall I answer it?
我已经向你的局长说过了
I've gone above you. I've spoken to your section chief.
将来你会谢我的 如果恨我 也无所谓
Someday you'll thank me. Or you won't. I don't care.
至少你还活着
You'll be alive.
帕齐督察?
Inspector Pazzi?
是史黛琳吗?
Is this Clarice?
哈罗 史黛琳
Hello, Clarice.
消息恐怕不太好
I'm afraid I have bad news for you.
-他死了吗?  -你收到我寄给你的信吗?
-Is he dead? -Did you get my note?
希望你喜欢那瓶手霜 是我特别替你订制的
I hope you like the skin cream. I had it specially made for you.
汉尼拔医生 他死了吗?
Is he dead, Dr. Lecter?
你要知道 我最喜欢和你聊天
I would love nothing more in this world than to be able to chat with you.
可惜现在实在不方便
Unfortunately, you've caught me at an awkward moment.
请原谅我
Please forgive me.
再见
See you around.
是个老朋友
An old friend.
好 别动
Okay, hold on.
咱们走吧
Here we go.
我走后门 必要时杀了他
I'll go around back! Kill him if you have to!
你喜欢哪样?
What's it to be?
是内脏在里面 还是...
Bowels in or bowels out
像犹大一样流得满地都是
likeJudas?
难道这又困扰你吗?
Are you confused?
那就由我来决定吧
I'll decide for you, if you'll permit me.
晚安
Good evening.
柯德
Cordell
依你看...
to you...
他的招手是表示再会呢
does that look like a wave good-bye
还是表示哈罗
or hello?
你是怎么想?
So, what do you think?
到底汉尼拔是想和她睡觉 杀她还是吃她呢?
Does Lecter want to fuck her or kill her or eat her or what?
也许三者都是
Probably all three.
只是不知道是什么顺序
Though I wouldn't want to predict in what order.
这是我的想法
Here's what I think.
不管巴尼加入多少浪漫的情节
No matter how Barney might want to romanticize it
把他们描述得像美女与野兽一般
and make it Beauty and the Beast
依我以前的经验来看
Lecter's object, as I know from personal experience
汉尼拔的目的永远是
has always been
让人逐渐崩溃
degradation
并且受尽痛苦
and suffering.
把这该死的面具拿走 搞得我不能呼吸
Get this damn thing off me. I can't breathe in this thing.
他常以良师益友的身份出现
He comes in the guise of a mentor
就像当初他对我和她一样
as he did with me and her.
痛苦会使他兴奋
But it's distress that excites him.
为了要引出他来
To draw him
就必须要让她痛苦
she needs to be distressed.
因为 当他看到她痛苦时就会现身
To make her attractive to him, let him see her distressed.
我要他在看到她的痛苦后
Let the damage he sees
而忍不住去伤害她
suggest the damage he could do.
就像狐狸听到兔子悲鸣时 会跑过去吃掉它
When the fox hears the rabbit scream, he comes a-runnin'.
而不会去帮助它
But not to help.
可是我不懂
I don't understand.
保罗 你不需要懂
There's nothing to understand, Paul.
只要知道你能拿不少钱就行了
All you have to understand is what it's worth to you.
不是 我不懂 以她诚实的个性
No, no, I don't understand why she didn't turn this over.
她应该会把它交出来的
I mean, she's such a straight arrow.
她没交出来 是因为没收到
She didn't turn it over because she didn't receive it.
她没收到 是因为没寄给她
She didn't receive it because it was never sent.
没寄给她 是因为汉尼拔没写
It was never sent because Lecter didn't write it.
他没写 是因为那是我写的
He didn't write it because I did.
你认为如何?
So, what do you think?
我觉得你最好别再帮她
You'd have been better off if you'd never got her out of trouble.
你管得也太多了 我是问你要多少钱?
Oh, woulda, shoulda, coulda. I meant, what do you think about the money?
五
Five.
让我们为这个五干一杯
Let's just toss it off, like "five."
你最好说清楚到底要多少
Let's say it with the respect it deserves.
我是说五十万
Five hundred thousand dollars.
很好 不多嘛
That's better, but not much.
-能成功吗?  -绝对可以
-Now, will it work? -It'll work.
可惜不会很好看
It won't be pretty.
那没关系
What ever is?
白痴
Cocksucker.
我从没见过这东西
Never seen this before in my life.
那为什么会在地下室 你的办公室里找到呢?
Then how do you account for its being found in your office, your basement?
你要我怎么回答
How do you want me to answer that, Mr. Krendler?
我根本没必要把它藏起来
What possible reason might I have to withhold it?
或许是因为它的内容
Perhaps because of the nature of its content.
念起来倒像封情书
Reads to me like a love letter.
-有没有查过指纹  -没有指纹
-Has it been tested for prints? -No prints on it. None on the last one.
笔迹分析呢?
Handwriting analysis?
"你有没有想过 为什么 那些庸俗的人无法了解你"
"Did you ever think, Clarice, why the philistines don't understand you?
"因为你就是参孙之谜"
It's because you're the answer to Samson's riddle.
"你是狮子里的蜜糖"
You are the honey in the lion."
很像他
Sounds like him to me.
你是说像同性恋? 我说像那个迷恋你的傻瓜
-Do you mean, like a homosexual? -Like a nut with a crush.
执政官诺门 我想说点...
Director Noonan, I need to say something...
史黛琳探员 我命令你暂时停职
Agent Starling, I am placing you on administrative leave
直到文件的分析 证明我们做出错误的决定为止
till document analysis tells me unequivocally a mistake's been made.
在此期间 你仍能享用医疗保险
In the meantime, you remain eligible for insurance and medical benefits.
把你的武器 和证件交给柏塞探员
Surrender your weapons and your identification to Agent Pearsall.
我有权力表达自己的想法
I want to say something. I think I'm entitled.
请讲
Go ahead.
我认为 维杰先生为了私人恩怨
I think Mr. Mason Verger is trying to capture Dr. Lecter
想要捉住汉尼拔医师
for the purposes of personal revenge.
我认为保罗先生和他勾结
I think Mr. Krendler is in collusion with him
利用调查局的资源 去帮助维杰先生
and wants the FBI's efforts against Dr. Lecter to work for Mr. Verger.
我更认为保罗先生已被人收买
I think Mr. Krendler is being paid to do this.
-好在你今天没有发誓  -少吓我 你去发誓呀!
-Lucky you're not sworn here today. -Swear me! You swear too!
史黛琳 如果证据不足
Clarice, if the evidence is lacking
你就能立即复职
you'll be entitled to full reinstatement without prejudice
但是你若采取不合作的态度
if you don't do or say anything in the meantime
那就没希望了
that would make that impossible.
史黛琳探员在调查局任职十年
Relieved of field duty pending an internal investigation
如今却被解除职务 等待内部调查
Special Agent Clarice Starling, a ten-year veteran on the Bureau
她的事业始于
began her career with an assignment
与致命狂人汉尼拔的会晤
to interview lethal madman Hannibal Lecter.
早先 我们听到 司法部发言人保罗的评论
Earlier, we heard comments from Justice Department spokesman Paul Krendler.
请你评论一下...
Can you comment on the Justice Department's...
今早司法部所做的决定
decision this morning?
调查局和司法部 都非常小心的处理此事
The FBI and theJustice Department are looking very carefully into the charges.
而且态度非常认真
And, yes, they are extremely serious.
我想加点自己的想法
I'd like to add a personal note, though.
-史黛琳是我们最好的探员之一  -不 你留下来
-Starling's one of our best agents. -No, no, no, stay.
我不相信这些控诉会成立
I would be very surprised if these accusations turn out to be true.
难道司法部和调查局 真的采取同一步调吗?
Is theJustice Department and FBI united in this decision?
现在还太早替她做结论
It's much too soon to condemn her
*佛利逊通讯*
乖狗
Good boy.
我觉得她很好
I think she's nice.
她对我一直很好 很有礼貌
She's always been nice to me. Polite.
难道你不同意
Don't you think?
巴尼 你知道鹞鸽是什么吗?
Do you know what a roller pigeon is, Barney?
鹞鸽喜欢飞得很高很快
Roller pigeons climb high and fast
然后翻着筋斗快速冲向地面
then roll over and fall just as fast towards the Earth.
鹞鸽又分成肤浅和深沉两种
There are shallow rollers and there are deep rollers
但是当两个深沉的鹞鸽结合时
but you can't breed two deep rollers, or their young, their offspring
它们的后代 往往会俯冲撞地而死
will roll all the way down, hit and die.
史黛琳探员是只深沉的鹞鸽
Agent Starling is a deep roller.
只希望她父母中 有一个是肤浅的鹞鸽
Let's hope one of her parents was not.
史黛琳 电话的电池快用完了
The power in that battery is low, Clarice.
为了不吵醒你 我没换
I would've changed it, but I didn't want to wake you.
你可以用充电器里的电池 但愿现在已经充好电了
Use the one in the charger. Hopefully, the light on it is green by now.
因为这通电话会很长 而我又不愿意中途被切断
Because this is gonna be a long call and I can't let you off
更因为 他们虽然剥夺了你的职责
because even though you've been stripped of your duties
但你一定会继续调查下去 绝不放弃
I know you won't abandon them  you'll try to put on a trace.
所以我们先挂断电话 好让你换电池
So we'll disconnect long enough for you to exchange the battery in the phone for the one in the charger.
三秒钟够吗?
Shall we say, three seconds?
-准备好了吗?  -好了
-Are you ready? -Yes.
开始
Go.
-很好  -谢谢你
-Very good. -Thank you.
在哥伦比亚区 被抓到无照带枪
Remember, Clarice, if you get caught with a concealed, unlicensed firearm
惩罚相当严重
in the District of Columbia, the penalty is very stiff.
不过如果你坚持那就带吧 现在到车里去
But bring the guns if you have to. Now get in your car.
我之所以这么做
The reason we're doing it like this, Clarice
是因为当我们谈话时 我希望你是清醒的
is because I like to watch you as we speak, with your eyes open.
别紧张 那不会使我兴奋 只会让我高兴而已
No, it does not excite me. It pleases me.
你的脚形很美
You have very shapely feet.
你现在在哪里?把街名念出来
Where are we now? Call it out.
麻萨诸塞街
Massachusetts Avenue.
到麻萨诸塞街去
Take it.
我们就拿你的感受做开场吧
I thought, to begin with, you might tell me how you're feeling.
那方面的?
About what?
例如你雇主如何对待你
The masters you serve and how they've treated you.
还有你的职业
Your career, such as it is.
甚至你的生命
Your life, Clarice.
我以为会谈你的事
I thought we might talk about yours.
-下面的横街叫什么?  -国会街
-What's the next cross street? -Capitol Street.
你在第二条街左转 把车停到火车站去
In two blocks, make a left into Union Station. Park.
我的生命?那有什么好谈
My life? What is there to say about mine?
我已冬眠了一段日子
I have been in a state of hibernation for some time
乏善可陈
a little inactive.
可是现在我回来了 既快乐又健康
But now I'm back home and I'm very happy and very healthy.
-倒是你让我很操心  -我很好
-You. It's you I'm worried about. -I'm fine.
不 你一点也不好
No, you're certainly not fine, Clarice.
你把自己奉献给调查局
You fell in love with the Bureau, the institution
然而在付出一切之后
only to discover, after giving it everything you've got
却发现他们并不喜欢你
that it does not love you back
这点让你愤愤不平
that, in fact, it resents you.
比放弃丈夫和孩子还要愤怒
It resents you more than the husband and children you gave up to it.
为什么?为什么你会这么愤怒
Why is that, do you think? Why are you so resented?
-你告诉我  -我告诉你?
-Tell me. -Tell you?
上帝会保祐你
God bless you.
你难道还看不出来
Well, isn't it clear?
你听命行事
You serve the idea of order, Clarice.
他们不是
They don't.
你遵守宣誓 他们不是
You believe in the oath you took. They don't.
你觉得保护弱小是你的责任 他们不是
You feel it is your duty to protect the sheep. They don't.
因为你的不同 所以他们不喜欢你
They don't like you because you're not like them.
他们对你又妒又恨
They hate you and envy you.
他们懦弱 任性 又无法无天
They are weak, unruly and believe in nothing.
*快速照相*
汉尼拔医生 维杰要杀你
Mason Verger wants to kill you, Dr. Lecter.
向我投降 我保证没人会伤害你
Turn yourself in to me, and I promise no one will hurt you.
你会握着我的手 和我一起待在监狱里吗?
Will you stay with me in my prison cell and hold my hand, Clarice?
那样一定很有意思
We could have some fun.
你错了 其实我更想杀维杰
No, Mason Verger does not want to kill me any more than I want to kill him.
他只想用 不可思议的方法来折磨我
He just wants to see me suffer in some unimaginable way.
是个无可救药的疯子
He is rather twisted, you know.
你见过他吗?
Have you had the pleasure of meeting him?
见过
Yes.
面对面?
Face-to-face, so to speak?
是的
Yes.
-他是不是很引人注意?  -汉尼拔医生
-Attractive, isn't he? -Dr. Lecter?
你在哪里?
Where are you?
好 再回来谈你
Okay, back to you.
如今所有你关心的东西 全被他们拿走了
I want to know what it is you think you will do
我想知道你打算怎么办
now that everything you've ever cared about has been taken away from you.
我不知道
I don't know, Dr. Lecter.
你能像你妈妈一样
Clarice, do you think you'll work as a chambermaid
到汽车旅馆里去
at a motel on Route 66
当打扫女工吗?
just like your mommy?
你在想什么?
What are you thinking now?
卸任的史黛琳探员 你在听我说话吗?
Are you paying attention to me, ex-Special Agent Starling?
还是想找出我的藏身处
Are you, by any chance, trying to trace my whereabouts?
-汉尼拔医生 我被跟踪了  -我已经看到他们
-I'm being followed, Dr. Lecter. -I know. I've seen them.
你现在真是左右为难
And now you're in a real dilemma, aren't you?
明知会引导他们找到我 难道你还要继续找吗?
Do you continue to try to find me, knowing that you are leading them to me?
还是你认为 自己真有能力
Do you have so much faith in your abilities that you honestly believe
能同时逮捕我们双方
you can somehow simultaneously arrest me and them?
不过结果可能会和 鲜鱼市场一样糟糕
It could get very messy, Clarice, like the fish market.
-让我来替你做 如何?  -做什么?
-What if I did it for you? -Did what?
伤害那些伤害过你的人
Harmed them, Clarice, the ones who have harmed you.
叫他们来求你的原谅
What if I made them scream apologies?
不 我真不该说
No, I shouldn't even say it
因为若以你的是非标准来衡量
because you'll feel, with your perfect grasp of right and wrong
恐怕会认为自己也是共犯
that you were somehow accompli.
别帮我
Don't help me.
当然不会 忘了我所说的
No, of course not. Forget I said it.
你很接近目标
Clarice, you were very, very warm.
非常接近
You were so close.
现在又偏了
And now you're getting colder again.
对 就是这儿
Yeah, warmer again.
好啦 给你的提示已经够多了
Well, I think I've been generous enough with you and the clues.
-你自己去找吧  -汉尼拔医生
-You're on your own now, Clarice. -Dr. Lecter.
希望你喜欢它们 回见
Hope you like them, Clarice. Ta-ta.
放进去
Go.
别挡住我!
Get out of the way!
我知道歇斯底里人的第一句话是"我没有歇斯底里"
I know the first thing a hysteric says is, "I am not a hysteric"...
但是我很镇静没有歇斯底里
but I am not a hysteric. I am calm.
我再问你一次 先想过再回答
I'll ask you one time. Think before you answer.
想想你以前的优良事迹
Think about every good thing you ever did.
想想你的宣誓
Think about what you swore.
有两个人在货车里 第三个开车 另一个倒地不起
Two men in a van, a third driving, another man down.
他们把他放在后面 我想是汉尼拔
They put him in the back. I think it was Lecter.
我给你车牌号码 并且会在 目击者面前再向你报告一次
I gave you a license, and I'm reporting it to you again in front of witnesses.
好吧
All right.
我将以绑架来处理
I'll go with it as a kidnapping.
我会派人和当地警员前往
I'll send someone with the local authorities...
希望他们 不会要我们出示搜索状
if they'll let us on the property without a warrant.
-我也去 你可以指定我为代表  -不行 你不能去
-I should go. You could deputize me. -No. You're not going.
你该回家等我电话
You're going home, where you'll wait for me to call...
如有发现我会马上告诉你
and tell you what, if anything, we've found.
谢谢维杰先生让我们查看 若有打扰的地方请原谅
Thank Mr. Verger for letting us look around. Sorry if we inconvenienced him.
放心 他随时都欢迎你们
He's always happy to see you.
我要打电话
Phone.
什么号码?
What number, please?
接卡罗
Carlo.
给我一杯
Give me one.
-他怎么样?  -在睡觉
-How is he? -Sleeping.
把他带回家吧
Bring him home.
这是史黛琳 请留话
You've reached Clarice Starling. Please leave a message.
史黛琳 接电话
Pick up, Starling.
那里一切正常
There was nothing out there.
我再重复一遍
I'm gonna say it again, in case you didn't hear me.
当你被停职时 就是普通百姓 而不是执法警官
You are not a law officer while you're on suspension. You'reJoe Blow.
为了你好 希望你正在洗澡
Hope for your sake you're in the bathroom.
巨大的...
Hylochoerus...
丛林猪
meinertzhageni.
高中的生物学中曾经提过 你还记得吗?
Ring any bells from high school biology, Doctor?
不记得了?
No?
让我把它的特徵告诉你
Well, I could list its most conspicuous features...
或许会唤起你的记忆
if that would help jog the memory.
有三对门牙...
Three pairs of incisors...
一对延长犬齿
one pair of elongated canines...
三对臼齿...
three pairs of molars...
四对前臼齿...
four pairs of premolars...
上下加起来...
upper and lower...
一共四十四颗牙
for a total of 44 teeth.
它们正餐前的开胃菜
The meal will begin with an hors d'oeuvres tartare...
就是生吃人脚
your feet.
主菜当然...是少了一双脚的你
The main course...the rest of you.
不过得在七个钟头后才开饭
won't be served until seven hours later.
在那段时间里...
But during that time...
我会为你全身会打满点滴...
you'll be able to enjoy the effects of the consumed appetizer...
好让你能清醒的感觉到 被生吃的痛楚
with a full-bodied saline drip.
我打赌你正在想...
I guess you wish now...
当初真该把我喂狗吃
you'd fed the rest of me to the dogs.
不会的
No, Mason.
我喜欢你现在这样
No, I much prefer you the way you are.
那么...
So...
晚餐就订在八点
dinner at 8:00.
柯德 今晚的娱乐活动...
You will stay for the evening's entertainment...
你会参加吧?
won't you, Cordell?
如果你不介意...
If it's all right with you...
我宁可不想参加
I think I'd rather not.
是宁可不...
Rather not...
还是宁愿不?
or will not?
你弟弟现在的味道 一定和你一样难闻
Your little brother must smell almost as badly as you do by now.
不准动 手举起来
Hold it! Hands where I can see 'em!
闭嘴
Quiet!
那是什么声音?
What was that?
柯德 快一点
Cordell, quickly!
趴下来
Get on your stomach.
史黛琳 晚安
Good evening, Clarice.
-像又回到往日一样  -闭嘴
-Just like old times. -Shut up.
-你能走吗?  -我会尽力
-Can you walk? -I can try.
你看起来不错
You look well.
现在给你松绑
I'm gonna cut you loose.
别碰我 否则我马上开枪
If you touch me, I'll shoot you.
-我了解  -不捣蛋你就能活着出去
-Understood. -Do right and you'll live through this.
语气和新教徒一样 最好快点
Spoken like a true Protestant. Better hurry.
把刀给我会快一点
Things might go faster if you hand me the knife.
第三个人在阁楼上
There was a third in the loft.
不 是我后面
No, Clarice. Behind me.
柯德 杀他 拿起枪 把他杀了
Cordell, shoot him! Get the gun and shoot him!
-到围栏里去  -当然！
-Go into the pen? -Yes!
不 我不要牵扯进去
No. I'm staying out of this.
不管怎样 你已经扯进来了 快去
You're involved, is what you are, in all of it. Now do it!
-不  -你快去！
-No. -Yes!
柯德 干脆把他推进去
Hey, Cordell, why don't you push him in?
到时推到我头上就行了
You can always say it was me.
柯德
Cordell.
柯德?
Cordell?
柯德！
Cordell!
玛莉 是我
Mary, it's me.
我决定提前下班 周末到湖边去住
I decided to take off early. I'll be at my lake house all weekend.
别把电话接过去 你听清楚了吗?
I don't want any calls forwarded either. Do you understand?
不管谁都让他们等 懂吗?
Whoever it is, they can all wait. Okay?
拜托这是国庆假日呀 谢谢你
Listen, it's 4th ofJuly, for Christ's sake. Thank you.
怎么搞的?
What the fuck?
很好 你带酒来了
Good. You brought the wine.
有一次我手里拿着 点燃的爆竹和朋友打赌
One time I bet a friend I could hold a lit firecracker in my hand...
赌我能拿得比他久
longer than he could.
你猜结果如何?
Can I guess?
你输了赌注 他丢了手指头 对不对?
You lost the bet, and he lost a finger. Am I right?
放心 不会痛的
This won't hurt a bit.
有客人要来吗?
Are we expecting guests?
我们已经追踪到电话 警方在十分钟内会到达
We've traced your call and units will be there in about ten minutes.
如果你能到屋外去最好
If you can do it safely, just get out of the house.
否则就继续和我通话
Otherwise, stay on the phone with me.
小姐?
Ma'am?
小姐 你仍在线上吗?
Are you there? Ma'am?
你必须让客人觉得温暖
You need to make sure they feel welcome.
-那是冬葱吗?  -还有续随子香料
-Are those shallots? -And caper berries.
奶油闻起来好香
That butter smells wonderful.
保罗 你饿了吗?
You feeling hungry, Paul?
好饿
Very.
主菜是什么?
What's the main course?
你不该问 那样就没有惊喜了
You should never ask. It spoils the surprise.
史黛琳 你起来干什么? 你应该休息 快回床上去
Clarice, what are you doing up? You should be resting. Get back to bed.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
-哈罗 保罗  -保罗 要有礼貌
-Hello, Paul. -Paul, don't be rude.
说"哈罗 史黛琳探员"
Say, "Hello, Agent Starling."
哈罗 史黛琳探员
Hello, Agent Starling.
我一直想看你吃饭
I always wanted to watch you eat.
你手里拿着什么 是想拿来砸我的头吗?
What have you got in your hand? Something to bash me on the head with?
把它放在桌子上
Put it on the table.
乖孩子
Good girl.
嘿 那是我的
Hey. That's mine.
坐下来
Now sit down.
史黛琳 我喜欢你的衣服
Hey, Clarice, love the dress.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
-保罗 你说呢?  -好
-What do you think, Paul? -Nice.
很好
Nice.
保罗 由你来说饭前祈祷文好吗?
Why don't you say grace, Paul?
-我?  -是的
-Me? -Yeah.
-祈祷文?  -没错
-Grace? -Sure.
好
Okay.
把头低下来
Bow your head.
天父 感谢你赐给我们食物...
Father, we thank Thee for Thy blessings...
以及你对他们的慈悲...
and dedicate them to Thy mercy...
我们将要接受圣餐...
We are about to receive...
请饶恕我们大家...
Forgive us all...
也饶恕史黛琳这种穷白鬼...
even white trash like Starling here...
并让她替我服务 阿门
and bring her into my service, amen.
我必须告诉你 即使是基督的 门徒保罗 说得也没你好
I have to tell you, Paul, even the Apostle Paul couldn't have done better.
他也讨厌女人
He hated women too.
-我能喝点酒吗?  -恐怕不好
-May I have some wine, please? -I don't think that's a good idea.
你身上还有吗啡
Not with the morphine.
你最好喝点汤
I think you should eat some broth. Okay?
顺便告诉你 祈祷文里有你的工作机会
By the way, that was a job offering I worked into the blessing.
因为我想进军众议院
I'm going to Congress, you know.
是吗?
Are you?
到我的竞选总部来
Come around campaign headquarters.
你可以做办公小姐 你会打字和存档吗?
You could be an office girl. Can you type and file?
会速记吗?把这个记下来
Can you take dictation? Take this down.
华盛顿充满了种田的乡下女人
Washington is full of corn pone, country pussy.
已经记下来 你早先说过了
I took it down. You said it already.
保罗 你变得很无礼 我讨厌无礼的家伙
Paul, now you're being rude, and I hate rude people.
乖孩子 先喝汤 来 吸一口
Drink your broth like a good boy. Come on. Sip.
很好
Good.
老兄呀 实在不好喝
It's not very good, buddy.
我加了点其他作料 可能和茴香的香味不调合
I admit I added something to yours. Perhaps it's clashing with the cumin.
但是保证你会爱死下道菜
But I assure you, the next course is to die for.
别这样
Come on, Clarice.
这才乖
That's a good girl.
很好
Good.
汉尼拔医生
Dr. Lecter.
你不用担心 其实脑本身没有痛楚感
You see, the brain itself feels no pain, Clarice, if that concerns you.
例如这是前头叶 就算保罗少了它也没有关系
For example, Paul won't miss this little piece here...part of the prefrontal lobe.
因为据说 它能使人有良好的态度
which they say is the seat of good manners.
你的档案在边界警局中 有五个重点
Your profile at the border stations has five features.
-我和你交换  -交换?
-I'll trade you. -Trade?
-放了他 我就告诉你那些资料  -你对交换两个字有什么感觉
-Stop, and I'll tell you what they are. -How does that word taste to you?
又冷又硬 就像在啜一枚油腻的硬币似的
Cheap and metallic, like sucking on a greasy coin?
-谁是克莉丝?  -就是史黛琳探员
-Who's Clarice? -Agent Starling, Paul.
如果你跟不上就别打岔
If you can't keep up with the conversation, try not to join in at all.
保罗 我就是史黛琳
Paul, I'm Starling.
你看...
See...
就在这里...
here...
脑子就在这个液囊之中
right here's the sac that contains the brain.
我真的需要喝点酒
I would really like some wine.
-很好闻  -没错
-That smells great. -Yes.
好了 要试一小块吗?
There. Like to try a little piece?
我是真的要喝点酒
I would really like some wine...
很好吃
It is good.
好 不过只能喝一点
All right. Just a little.
喝吧
Okay?
只要有机会 你连我的命都会要 对不对?
Given the chance, you would deny me my life, wouldn't you?
不是你的命
Not your life.
那是自由罗 你要把我的自由拿走
My freedom, just that. You'd take that from me.
就算你这么做 他们会要你回去吗?
And if you did, would they have you back, do you think?
我是说调查局?
The FBI?
你蔑视的人同样也轻视你?
Those people you despise almost as much as they despise you?
你想他们会给你奖章吗?
Will they give you a medal, Clarice, do you think?
然后你把它装框挂在墙上...
Would you have it professionally framed and hang it on your wall to look at...
每天看着它 提醒自己 有多勇敢和清廉吗?
and remind you of your courage and incorruptibility?
果真如此 一面镜子就够了
All you would need for that, Clarice, is a mirror.
伶牙俐齿的人我另有用处 我永远不会再雇用你
I have plans for that smart mouth. I'm never gonna hire you now.
保罗 我告诉过你
Remember what I said?
如果对客人不礼貌
If you can't be polite to our guests...
就要到小孩桌去坐
you have to sit at the kiddies' table.
史黛琳 你别起来
Don't get up, Clarice.
保罗会帮我收拾和煮咖啡
Paul will help me clear and make the coffee.
你仔细想想我说的话
Just think about what I said, Clarice.
咖啡
Coffee.
我绕了半个地球
I came halfway around the world...
就为了看你如何释放自己
to watch you run, Clarice.
释放我 好吗?
Let me run, huh?
史黛琳 会不会有一天你对我说...
Tell me, Clarice, would you ever say to me...
"别这么做"
"Stop.
"如果爱我 就别这么做"
If you loved me, you'd stop"?
永远不会
Not in a thousand years.
好个永远不会
我就欣赏你这点
That's my girl.
史黛琳 我必须承认你不简单
Now, that's really interesting, Clarice...
而我的时间又很紧迫
and I'm really pressed for time.
告诉我钥匙在哪里
So where's the key?
钥匙呢?
Where's the key?
好
Okay.
你要切在...
Above...
手腕的上面...
or below the wrist...
还是下面?
Clarice?
这次绝对会很疼
This is really gonna hurt.
把手举起来
Show me your hands!
说明你的身份
Identify yourself!
我是克莉丝史黛琳
I'm Clarice Starling!
调查局探员
FBI!
-嗨  -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
那是什么?
What's that?
那是鱼子酱
That's caviar.
-那些呢?  -无花果
-What are those? -These are figs.
那个呢?
And that?
这个吗?
This?
我想你不会喜欢
That I don't think you would like.
-看起来很好吃  -是很好吃
-It looks good. -Oh, it is good.
我能尝尝吗?
Can I have some?
你是个很奇怪的孩子
You're a very unusual boy, aren't you?
我不喜欢吃他们给我的食物
I couldn't eat what they gave me.
依我看来那根本不是食物
Nor should you. It isn't even food as I understand the definition,
所以我才自己带吃的来
which is why I always bring my own.
那么你想吃哪一种?
So, which would you like to try?
我想应该没关系吧
Well, I suppose it's all right.
毕竟 你我的妈妈都曾说过这句话
After all, as your mother tells you, and my mother certainly told me...
我记得她常说"重要的是..."
"It is important," she always used to say...
"要不断尝试不同的东西"
"always to try new things."
嘴张开
Open up.